A Guide to the National Committee on United States-China Relations records, RG 5, Accession 5 FA1187
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Development, 1964-2007; 10
  - National Endowment for the Humanities (NEH) (Bay Area China Education Project), 1974-1975 (Box 51, Folder 497-498)
  - National Endowment for the Humanities (NEH) (Bay Area China Education Project - Grant Accounting), 1973-1975 (Box 51, Folder 499)
  - National Endowment for the Humanities (NEH) (Archaeological Exhibit ), 1974-1976 (Box 51, Folder 500-501)
  - National Endowment for the Humanities (NEH) (Archaeological Exhibit - Grant Accounting), 1974-1975, 1978 (Box 51, Folder 502)
  - Rockefeller Brothers Fund, 1966-1974 (Box 51, Folder 503)
  - Rockefeller Brothers Fund, 1975-1992, 1999 (Box 52, Folder 504-505)
  - Rockefeller Brothers Fund (Payments), 1967-1969 (Box 52, Folder 506)
    Includes personal contribution in 1967 from John D. Rockefeller 3.
  - Rockefeller Foundation, 1966-1967, 1970-1987 (Box 52, Folder 507-509)
    Includes copy of Selskar Gunn's 1934 report on "China and the Rockefeller Foundation."
  - Smith Richardson Foundation (Chinese Foreign Security Project), 1996-1999 (Box 52, Folder 510-512)
    Grant for project on the "Making of Chinese Foreign and Security Policy in the Era of Reform: 1978-2000." File includes book manuscript.
  - Receipt of Contributions (Fiscal Year 2004), 2003 October - 2004 September (Box 53, Folder 515)
    Acknowledgement letters.
  - Receipt of Contributions (Fiscal Year 2005), 2004 October - 2005 September (Box 53, Folder 516-518)
  - Receipt of Contributions (Fiscal Year 2006), 2005 October - 2006 September (Box 53, Folder 519)
  - Receipt of Contributions (Fiscal Year 2006), 2005 October - 2006 September (Box 54, Folder 520)
  - Receipt of Contributions (Stub Year), 2006 October-December (Box 54, Folder 521)
  - Receipt of Contributions (Calendar Year 2007), 2007 January-April (Box 54, Folder 522)
- Board of Directors, Committees, and Members records, 1950, 1964-2007; 11
  The Board of Directors, Committees, and Members records series in RG 5 contains the Board Minutes and Materials (mailings and memos) from its start in 1966 to 2007. Most of the files usefully include a detailed list of contents or divisions within the annual files. In addition to meeting minutes, materials include interim correspondence, nomination and membership lists, financial and audit reports, and frequently include cumulative lists of exchanges, as well as various trip or project reports.
  Other records in the series include some early organizational and program planning files, as well as a reference file on the Committee of One Million, which opposed the admission of Red China to the United Nations. Finally, the series includes a set of files on former corporate members (1970s-1980s), and a few early membership files.
  - Former Corporate Members: A, 1971-1993 (Box 31, Folder 321)
    American Can Corporation, 1983-1986, Ampex Corporation, undated, Anrig, Gregory R. (Deceased), 1978-1985, 1993, Archer Daniels Midland Company, 1972-1975, Arthur D. Little, Inc., 1971-1974
  - Former Corporate Members: B, 1971-1987 (Box 31, Folder 322)
    Bank of America, 1971-1979, Bank of China, 1987, Bank of Credit and Commerce International, 1986-1987, Bendix Corporation, 1973-1976, Boeing, 1973-1974, Brownstein Zeidman and Schomer, 1982, Burlington Northern, Inc., 1982-1984.
  - Former Corporate Members: Ca - Cg, 1971-1987 (Box 31, Folder 323)
    Carl Marks and Company, 1978-1987, Caterpillar Tractor Co., 1971-1973, 1979, Central National Corporation, 1975, 1980-1986.
  - Former Corporate Members: Chase Manhattan Bank, 1973-1986 (Box 31, Folder 324)
  - Former Corporate Members: China - Commerce, 1972-1986 (Box 31, Folder 325)
    China Consultants International Ltd., 1972-1973, Commerce Consultants International Ltd., 1985-1986.
  - Former Corporate Members: Committee for New China Policy, 1969-1972 (Box 32, Folder 326)
  - Former Corporate Members: Con - CZ, 1972-1987 (Box 32, Folder 327)
    Continental Can Company, 1973, Control Data Corporation, 1985-1987, CPC International, 1972-1974.
  - Former Corporate Members: D - E, 1973-1987 (Box 32, Folder 328)
    Leo A. Daly Company, 1985-1987, Deere and Company, 1974-1985, Diebold Group, Inc., 1973-1976, Eli Lilly International Corp., 1986, Esquire, Inc., 1978-1982.
  - Former Corporate Members: F, 1971-1986 (Box 32, Folder 329)
    Federated Department Stores, Inc., 1975, 1980-1985, First National Bank of Boston, 1971-1972, Ford Motor Company, 1973-1979, 1981, Fuqua World Trade Corporation, 1986.
  - Former Corporate Members: G - H, 1973-1987 (Box 32, Folder 330)
    General Electric Company, 1985-1987, General Foods Corporation, 1981-1986, Goody Products, Inc., 1985-1987, Gulf Oil Corporation, 1979-1986, Han D (H & D) Transmission Service International, Inc., 1979-1986, Hardy Salt Company, 1973-1976.
  - Former Corporate Members: I - L, 1975-1987 (Box 32, Folder 331)
    Index Systems Inc., 1986-1987, Ingersoll-Rand Company, 1979-1982, Insilco Corporation, 1982-1984, Japan Air Lines, 1975-1984.
  - Former Corporate Members: M - N, 1971-1987 (Box 32, Folder 332)
    Madison Square Garden Corporation, 1978-1981, Manufacturers Hanover Trust Company,1973-1982, MobilOIl /Mobil South, Inc., 1984-1986, Moran, Stahl and Boyer, 1987, National Cash Register Corporation, 1974-1985, NL Inducstries, Inc., 1971-1974, 1982, Northwest Airlines, 1974-1982.
  - Former Corporate Members: O - P, 1971-1986 (Box 32, Folder 333)
    Pacific Telesis International, 1985-1986, Pakistan International Airlines, 1978-1979, Pan American World Airways, 1978-1985, Parsons and Whittemore, Inc., 1971-1972, Paschall International Corporation, 1972-1973, Peabody International Corporation, 1985-1986, Pfizer, Inc., 1974-1975, Plenum Publishing Corporation, 1973-1975. File for Paschall International includes report on June 1971 "Chairman's Visit to the People's Republic of China" [by G. Arnold Hart, chairman, Bank of Montreal?].
  - Annual Members Dinner, 1972 May 16 (Box 39, Folder 393)
    Includes Executive Committee minutes. February 1, 1972, and transcript of speech by John Richardson, Jr.
  - National Committee on United States - China Relations: First-Year Report, 1966 (Box 39, Folder 394)
  - National Committee on United States - China Relations: Program Summary, 1967-1968 (Box 39, Folder 395)
  - Committee of One Million, 1950-1971 (Box 39, Folder 396-399)
    Committee of One Million against the Admission of Communist China to the United Nations.
  - FA1187:021 - Committee of One Million, 1964; Oversized: 2 broadsides (approx. 17" x 22") on newsprint. (Folder Oversized 2)
    Two broadsides from the Committee of One Million,urging opposition to China's admission to the U. N.
  - FA1187:022 - Committee of One Million, 1968; Oversized: Newsletter (11.5" x 16.25") (Box 64, Folder 397)
    Christian Economics newsletter, 1968 April 16, with address label for "Rev M L King Jr."
  - FA1187:023 - Committee of One Million, 1966, 1968; Oversized: 2 broadsides (approx. 15.5" x 23") (Folder Oversized 2)
    Copies of two full-page ads in the New York Times: "An Open Letter to the American People on the 'China Debate'" (from faculty and scholars in the Republic of China), 1966 September 6, and ad by the Clergymen's Committee on China, 1968 November 18 ("Millions of Americans are distressed and Confused... ").
  - Membership: General, 1966-1968 (Box 54, Folder 523)
    Reference file of clippings and correspondence relating to potential members.
  - Program Proposals, 1966 (Box 54, Folder 524)
    Includes proposal for discussion at Development Committee meeting, September 9, [1966].
  - Program Planning (General), 1967-1969 (Box 54, Folder 525)
    Miscellaneous correspondence with Robert Scalapino and others concerning program direction and planning, membership, and fundraising.
  - National Committee on United States - China Relations, Organizational History and Program Summary, 1966-1967 (Box 54, Folder 526)
  - National Committee on United States - China Relations, Annual Report and Program Summary, 1967-1968, 1968-1969 (Box 54, Folder 527)
  - Board Minutes and Materials, 1966 (Box 54, Folder 528)
  - Board Minutes and Materials, 1967 (Box 54, Folder 529-530)
  - Board Minutes and Materials, 1968 (Box 55, Folder 531-532)
  - Board Minutes and Materials, 1969 (Box 55, Folder 533-534)
  - Board Minutes and Materials, 1970 (Box 55, Folder 535-536)
  - Board Minutes and Materials, 1971 (Box 55, Folder 537)
  - Board Minutes and Materials, 1972 (Box 55, Folder 538)
  - Board Minutes and Materials, 1973 (Box 56, Folder 539)
  - Board Minutes and Materials, 1974 (Box 56, Folder 540-541)
  - Board Minutes and Materials, 1975 (Box 56, Folder 542-543)
  - Board Minutes and Materials, 1976-1977 (Box 56, Folder 544)
  - Board Minutes and Materials, 1978 (Box 56, Folder 545)
  - Board Minutes and Materials, 1979 (Box 56, Folder 546)
  - Board Minutes and Materials, 1980 (Box 57, Folder 547-548)
  - Board Minutes and Materials, 1981 (Box 57, Folder 549-550)
  - Board Minutes and Materials, 1982 (Box 57, Folder 551)
  - Board Minutes and Materials, 1983 (Box 57, Folder 552)
  - Board Minutes and Materials, 1984 (Box 57, Folder 553-554)
  - Board Minutes and Materials, 1985 (Box 57, Folder 555)
  - Board Minutes and Materials, 1986 (Box 58, Folder 556)
  - Board Minutes and Materials, 1987 (Box 58, Folder 557-558)
  - Board Minutes and Materials, 1988 (Box 58, Folder 559-560)
  - Board Minutes and Materials, 1989 (Box 58, Folder 561-562)
  - Board Minutes and Materials, 1990 (Box 58, Folder 563)
  - Board Minutes and Materials, 1990 (Box 59, Folder 564-565)
  - Board Minutes and Materials, 1991 (Box 59, Folder 566-569)
  - Board Minutes and Materials, 1992 (Box 59, Folder 570-571)
  - Board Minutes and Materials, 1993 (Box 60, Folder 572-574)
  - Board Minutes and Materials, 1994 (Box 60, Folder 575-577)
  - Board Minutes and Materials, 1995 (Box 60, Folder 578-579)
  - Board Minutes and Materials, 1995 (Box 61, Folder 580)
  - Board Minutes and Materials, 1996 (Box 61, Folder 581-582)
  - Board Minutes and Materials, 1997 (Box 61, Folder 583-585)
  - Board Minutes and Materials, 1998 (Box 61, Folder 586-587)
  - Board Minutes and Materials, 1999 (Box 61, Folder 588)
  - Board Minutes and Materials, 1999 (Box 62, Folder 589)
  - Board Minutes and Materials, 2000 (Box 62, Folder 590-591)
  - Board Minutes and Materials, 2001 (Box 62, Folder 592-593)
  - Board Minutes and Materials, 2002 (Box 62, Folder 594-595)
  - Board Minutes and Materials, 2003-2007 (Box 62, Folder 596-598)
    Materials include minutes and financial reports, but consist mainly of correspondence and updates addressed to the board. The files for 2003-2007 appear to be less comprehensive than the board materials files for earlier years.
- Clippings and Reference, 1960-2012; 15
  The Clippings and Reference series in RG 5 contains various topical files relating to law, policy, and development, as well as files on Chinese government, politics, and political leaders, issues, and movements. Materials consist of newspaper and magazine clippings, papers, articles, and press releases.
  - General Policy - Domestic, 1969-1979 (Box 18, Folder 182)
  - General Policy - Domestic, 1980-1984 (Box 19, Folder 183)
    Includes material on the March 1982 State Council shuffle and new Constitution.
  - Ideology: Major Reports and General Articles, 1975-1985 (Box 19, Folder 184-185)
  - Ideology: Specific Issues, 1975-1984 (Box 19, Folder 186)
  - Insurance, 1980-1982 (Box 19, Folder 187)
  - Law: Criminal Justice, 1969-1980 (Box 19, Folder 188)
  - Legal System, 1977-1986 (Box 19, Folder 189)
    Includes paper by Stanley B. Lubman, "China's Formal Legal System: Institutions and Policies," 1980, and reflections by U. S. lawyers on law in China.
  - Maritime Law, Ports, and Shipbuilding, 1974-1984 (Box 19, Folder 190)
  - Tourism: General, 1979-1985 (Box 20, Folder 191)
    Tourist Industry statistics,new sites, hotels, procedures.
  - Tourism: Mountaineering, 1980-1982 (Box 20, Folder 192)
  - Transportation, 1972-1986 (Box 20, Folder 193)
  - Urban Planning: General, 1977-1986 (Box 20, Folder 194)
  - Urban Planning: Major Reports, 1960-1982 (Box 20, Folder 195)
  - Urban Planning: Construction and Housing, 1978 (Box 20, Folder 196)
  - Government, 1978-1985 (Box 20, Folder 197)
    Party and government structure.
  - Constitutions, 1975-1982 (Box 20, Folder 198)
  - Fourth and Fifth National People's Congresses, 1975, 1978-1981 (Box 20, Folder 199)
    Results and Commentary.
  - Sixth National People's Congress, 1983 (Box 20, Folder 200)
  - Ninth - Eleventh National Congress of the Communist Party of China, 1969-1981 (Box 21, Folder 201)
  - Twelfth National Congress of the Communist Party of China, 1982 (Box 21, Folder 202)
  - Issues: Confucius, 1974-1984 (Box 21, Folder 203)
  - Issues: Corruption, 1980-1985 (Box 21, Folder 204)
  - Issues: Cultural Revolution, 1968-1984 (Box 21, Folder 205)
  - Issues: De-Maoification, 1976-1985 (Box 21, Folder 206)
  - Issues: Dissent, 1976-1982 (Box 21, Folder 207)
  - Issues: 1972 (Nixon Visit) (Box 21, Folder 208)
  - Issues: Gang of Four, 1977-1981 (Box 21, Folder 209)
  - Issues: Lin Piao Affair, 1971-1983 (Box 21, Folder 210)
  - Issues: Political Vietnam Refugees, 1979-1984 (Box 21, Folder 211)
  - China Spring Movement, 1982-1983 (Box 21, Folder 212)
  - Radicals vs. Moderates, 1971 - 1976 (Box 21, Folder 213)
    Including death of Zhou Enlai.
  - Reagan Administration, 1980-1984 (Box 21, Folder 214)
    Ronald Reagan campaign and election, George Bush visit, 1980, reactions.
  - Deng Xiaoping Visit, 1979 (Box 22, Folder 215)
    To U. S. and Washington, DC.
  - Deng Xiaoping, 1986-1997 (Box 43, Folder 436)
  - Deng Xiaoping, 1986-1997 (Box 44, Folder 437)
  - Taiwan, 1994-2012 (Box 44, Folder 438-440)
    Includes 2009 survey by Committee of 100, Still The 'Other'? Public Attitudes toward Chinese and Asian Americans, papers and Jan Berris notes from Conference on U. S. Taiwan Policy Consultation, 1994.
  - Three Gorges Dam, 1992-2001 (Box 44, Folder 441)
  - Tibet, 1988-2001 (Box 44, Folder 442)
  - Tibet, 1980-2002 (Box 45, Folder 443-444)